Hello, everyone.
大家好。
Welcome to another lesson at EnglishPod.
欢迎来到 EnglishPod 的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
Katerina My name is Katerin.
Katerina 我是 Katerina。
So, Marco, what are we talking about today?
那么，Marco，我们今天要聊什么？
Marco Today, we're going to be talking about a popular
Marco 今天，我们要讨论一个全世界都
topic all over the world and that is smoking.
热门的话题，那就是吸烟。
Katerina Well, not so popular in the States right
Katerina 嗯，说实话，现在在美国可没那么
now, to be honest.
热门。
Marco Well, that's the thing.
Marco 嗯，这就是问题所在。
In every country in the world now, they are becoming more strict on smoking and where
现在世界上每个国家都对吸烟和
you can smoke.
吸烟地点越来越严格。
So, it's becoming very difficult for smokers nowadays.
所以，现在对吸烟者来说越来越难了。
Katerina Well, it's a good reason to want to quit.
Katerina 嗯，这是个想戒烟的好理由。
Marco And that's what we're going to be talking
Marco 我们今天要讨论的
about today is quitting smoking.
就是戒烟。
Katerina Well, before we get going, we do have a really
Katerina 在我们开始之前，我们有一个非常
important phrase that we should preview in today's vocabulary preview.
重要的短语要在今天的词汇预览中先看一下。
Vocabulary Preview Marco Alright, so on vocabulary preview, we're
词汇预览 Marco 好的，在词汇预览中，我们
going to take a look at this word pack of smokes.
要看看这个词“pack of smokes”。
Katerina Pack of smokes.
Katerina “Pack of smokes”。
So, Marco A pack of smokes.
所以，Marco “A pack of smokes”。
Katerina So, smokes is a word for cigarettes.
Katerina 所以，“smokes”是香烟的另一种说法。
It's the same thing, smokes or cigarettes.
意思一样，“smokes”或“cigarettes”。
Marco Right, but a pack is, you know, like 20 cigarettes.
Marco 对，但“pack”就是一包，比如20支香烟。
Katerina It's a box of cigarettes.
Katerina 就是一盒香烟。
You buy them in a pack.
你按包买。
You don't just buy one at a time.
你不会一次只买一支。
So, again, the phrase is pack of smokes.
所以，再说一遍，这个短语是“pack of smokes”。
Marco Pack of smokes.
Marco “Pack of smokes”。
So, why don't we listen to our dialogue for the first time and see what's going on with
那么，我们第一次听一下对话，看看这个
this smoker.
吸烟者发生了什么。
Smoker Ah, it smells like an ashtray in here.
吸烟者 啊，这里闻起来像个烟灰缸。
Smoker Hi, honey.
吸烟者 嗨，亲爱的。
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Why do you have that look on your face?
你为什么脸上是那种表情？
Smoker What's wrong?
吸烟者 怎么了？
I thought we agreed you were going to quit smoking.
我以为我们同意你要戒烟了。
Smoker No.
吸烟者 不。
I said I was going to cut down, which is very different.
我说的是我要减少吸烟，这很不一样。
You can't just expect me to go cold turkey overnight.
你不能指望我一下子就彻底戒烟。
Katerina Look, there are other ways to quit.
卡捷琳娜：听着，戒烟还有其他方法。
You can try the nicotine patch or nicotine chewing gum.
你可以试试尼古丁贴片或尼古丁口香糖。
We spend a fortune on cigarettes every month, and now laws are cracking down and not allowing
我们每个月在香烟上花一大笔钱，现在法律也在严厉打击，
smoking in any public place.
任何公共场所都不允许吸烟。
It's not like you can just light up like before.
你不能再像以前那样随便点烟了。
Smoker I know, I know.
吸烟者：我知道，我知道。
I really am trying, but I don't have the willpower to just quit.
我真的在努力，但我没有意志力就这么戒掉。
I can't fight with the urge to reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee
我无法抵抗早上喝咖啡时或午饭后
or after lunch.
伸手拿烟包的冲动。
Please understand.
请理解我。
Katerina Fine.
卡捷琳娜：好吧。
I want a divorce.
我要离婚。
Katerina Sorry, I just smoked a pack of cigarettes.
卡捷琳娜：抱歉，我刚抽了一包烟。
Smoker You do smoke, don't you?
吸烟者：你确实抽烟，对吧？
Katerina Well, we'll talk about that later.
卡捷琳娜：嗯，我们晚点再谈这个。
Smoker Alright, so it is a little bit extreme, though.
吸烟者：好吧，不过这也太极端了。
I mean, he's divorcing her because she won't quit.
我是说，他要跟她离婚，就因为她不肯戒烟。
Katerina Well, some people really are health conscious
卡捷琳娜：嗯，有些人真的很注重健康，
and are afraid of the negative side of smoking, which has a lot of health side effects.
而且害怕吸烟的负面影响，吸烟有很多健康副作用。
Smoker Yeah.
吸烟者：是啊。
Well, as he was complaining about all the negative effects and the negative aspects
嗯，在他抱怨吸烟的所有负面效果和负面影响时，
of smoking, he did mention, both of them mentioned a lot of great words and phrases.
他们俩都提到了很多很棒的词和短语。
So why don't we take a look at them now in Language Takeaway?
那我们不如在“语言要点”环节看看这些词吧？
Katerina Language Takeaway.
卡捷琳娜：语言要点。
Well, this first word is a word that's very important for any smoker who goes to a bar
嗯，第一个词对任何去酒吧或餐厅的吸烟者来说都很重要，
or restaurant and needs to put the ash somewhere, right?
因为他们需要找个地方放烟灰，对吧？
So when you smoke, there's some ash, there's some messy, dirty stuff, and you need an ashtray
所以当你吸烟时，会有一些烟灰，一些脏乱的东西，你需要一个烟灰缸
to collect it.
来收集它们。
Smoker An ashtray.
吸烟者：烟灰缸。
Katerina So an ashtray is something that's usually
卡捷琳娜：所以烟灰缸通常是
round or square and you put it on a table and it's just very helpful to keep the house
圆形或方形的，你把它放在桌子上，它很有助于保持家里
clean or restaurant clean.
或餐厅的清洁。
So if you're in a restaurant, you say, hey, can I have an ashtray, please?
所以如果你在餐厅，你会说，嘿，能给我一个烟灰缸吗？
Smoker So the residue or the stuff that when you're
吸烟者：所以残留物或你吸烟时
smoking it comes out the gray, I don't know, like dust, it's called ash.
冒出来的灰色东西，我不知道，像灰尘一样，它叫烟灰。
Katerina Right.
卡捷琳娜：对。
And this is a tray.
而这是一个托盘。
But the complaint here is, it smells like an ashtray in here.
但这里的抱怨是，这里闻起来像个烟灰缸。
That means it smells really, really bad in here.
意思是这里闻起来非常非常难闻。
Smoker Yeah, it smells like cigarettes.
吸烟者：是啊，闻起来有烟味。
Katerina Yeah.
卡捷琳娜：嗯。
So that word again is ashtray.
所以那个词又是“ashtray”。
Smoker Ashtray.
吸烟者：烟灰缸。
All right.
好的。
Well, and the guy was complaining and he said, well, I thought you were going to quit smoking.
嗯，那个家伙在抱怨，他说，我以为你要戒烟了。
And she said, no, no, I said I was going to cut down.
她说，不，不，我说的是我要减少吸烟量。
Katerina She says it's very different from quitting
卡捷琳娜：她说这和戒烟很不一样。
smoking.
吸烟。
So Marco, maybe we should talk about how cutting down and quitting are different.
所以马可，也许我们应该谈谈减少吸烟和戒烟有什么不同。
Smoker All right.
吸烟者：好的。
So if I say I'm going to cut down on smoking, it's just I'm going to smoke less.
所以如果我说我要减少吸烟，那只是说我抽得少一些。
Katerina Okay, so let's take an example.
卡捷琳娜：好的，那我们举个例子。
I smoke 10 cigarettes a day, but I want to cut down.
我一天抽10支烟，但我想减少。
How many should I smoke later?
那我以后应该抽多少？
Maybe?
大概？
Smoker Like two or three.
吸烟者：像两三支。
Katerina Two or three.
卡捷琳娜：两三支。
Smoker Instead of quitting.
吸烟者：而不是戒烟。
So if you quit smoking, that would mean zero.
所以如果你戒烟，那就意味着零支。
Katerina Zero cigarettes, no smoking anymore.
卡捷琳娜：零支烟，不再抽烟了。
Smoker Right.
吸烟者：对。
Katerina All right.
卡捷琳娜：好的。
So you can also cut down on carbs like carbohydrates.
所以你也可以减少碳水化合物，比如碳水。
So some people who cut down on carbs eat less bread.
所以一些减少碳水的人会少吃面包。
They don't eat any pasta.
他们不吃任何意面。
So these are really good ways of trying to talk about dieting as well as smoking.
这些都是谈论节食和吸烟的好方法。
Smoker Right.
吸烟者：对。
And I think we have a couple of examples of other ways we can use this phrase cut down.
我想我们还有几个例子，可以用这个短语“cut down”。
So let's listen to them now.
那我们来听听它们。
Example 1.
例子1。
Our company has decided to cut down our workload.
我们公司决定减少工作量。
So from now on, we leave at 3pm every Friday.
所以从现在开始，我们每周五下午3点下班。
Example 2.
例子2。
You should really cut down on the amount of salt you eat.
你真的应该减少盐的摄入量。
It's not good for you.
这对你不好。
Example 3.
例子3。
My doctor told me I need to cut down on fatty foods because of my heart condition.
我的医生告诉我，因为我的心脏问题，我需要减少高脂肪食物。
Katerina And when you want to smoke a cigarette, you
卡捷琳娜：当你想抽烟时，
have to do something first with some fires.
你得先做点什么事，跟火有关。
We call this lighting up.
我们称之为“点亮”。
Smoker To light up.
吸烟者 点烟。
Katerina So lighting up, it doesn't mean turning on
Katerina 所以“点亮”并不意味着打开开关。
the light.
灯光。
It actually means using a lighter or some fire to start your cigarette.
它实际上是指用打火机或火来点烟。
Smoker Right.
吸烟者 没错。
So you want to light up with the lighter matches or some sort of fire.
所以你想用打火机、火柴或某种火源来点燃。
Katerina The man says, the husband says, it's not
卡特琳娜 那个男人，也就是丈夫说，这不是
like you can just light up like before.
就像以前那样，你随时可以点烟。
That means it's not like you can just smoke like before.
这意味着你不能像以前那样随便抽烟了。
So in some cases, light up means to smoke a cigarette.
所以在某些情况下，light up 指的是点烟抽。
We're in a movie theater and someone lights a cigarette and I say, oh, you can't light
我们在电影院里，有人点了一支烟，然后我说，哦，你不能点烟。
up in here.
在这里。
Smoker Right.
吸烟者 没错。
So you can't smoke in here.
所以你不能在这里抽烟。
Katerina You can't smoke in here.
卡特琳娜 你不能在这里抽烟。
Smoker It's another way of saying smoking.
Smoker 这是吸烟的另一种说法。
Very good.
很好。
And she was explaining, you know, how difficult it is and she's trying to quit.
她解释说，你知道，这有多难，而且她正在努力戒掉。
But she said, I don't have the willpower to just quit.
但是她说，我没有意志力直接戒掉。
Katerina Ooh, willpower.
卡捷琳娜 哦，意志力。
So this is an important word.
所以这是一个重要的词。
Smoker Willpower.
吸烟者的意志力。
Katerina Willpower.
卡特琳娜·威尔帕沃。
You think of the main part of this word is will.
你认为这个词的主要部分是“will”。
That means the desire to do something.
那意味着做某事的欲望。
You want to do something.
你想做点什么。
Smoker So if I have willpower, I have strong willpower.
吸烟者 所以如果我有意志力，我有很强的意志力。
What am I saying?
我在说什么呢？
Katerina You're saying that you can make a decision and you can follow your decision.
卡特琳娜 你是说你可以做出决定，并且能够坚持自己的决定。
So I decide not to eat cake.
所以我决定不吃蛋糕了。
I have very strong willpower, so I never eat cake.
我有很强的意志力，所以我从不吃蛋糕。
If I don't have strong willpower, maybe I sometimes secretly eat cake in the middle
如果我没有很强的意志力，也许我有时会偷偷在半夜吃蛋糕。
of the night from my refrigerator.
从我的冰箱里拿出来的，在夜里。
Smoker So that happens, right?
吸烟者 所以这种事确实会发生，对吧？
Sometimes you don't have strong enough willpower.
有时候你的意志力不够强大。
So you kind of eat a little bit of cake when nobody's watching.
所以你会趁没人注意的时候偷偷吃一小块蛋糕。
Katerina Exactly.
卡特琳娜 没错。
And you can have willpower about lots of different things.
你可以对很多事情拥有意志力。
So this is a great word again to use when you're talking about dieting or smoking or
所以这又是一个很好的词，当你谈论节食或戒烟时可以用到。
drinking.
喝酒。
Smoker Any type of maybe temptation.
任何可能诱惑的东西，比如烟。
Katerina Exactly.
卡捷琳娜：没错。
Smoker All right.
抽烟者：好吧。
And well, she said she had this urge to reach for her pack of smokes.
她说她有种冲动想去拿她的烟盒。
Katerina Ooh, urge is another good one.
卡捷琳娜：哦，“冲动”这个词也不错。
It's very similar to willpower, but an urge is kind of like a physical feeling that makes
它和“意志力”很相似，但冲动更像是一种身体上的感觉，让你
you want to do something.
想做某件事。
Smoker So you have like this strong desire.
抽烟者：所以你有一种强烈的欲望。
Katerina So I have the urge to go swimming today.
卡捷琳娜：所以今天我有冲动去游泳。
I don't know why, but I really want to.
我也不知道为什么，但我真的很想去。
Smoker All right.
抽烟者：好吧。
You have an urge.
你有一种冲动。
Interesting word.
有趣的词。
Katerina Pregnant women often have these kinds of things
卡捷琳娜：孕妇经常会有这种情况，
too.
也是。
I have the urge to do something.
我有冲动去做某事。
We also call them cravings.
我们也称之为“渴望”。
Smoker Oh, cravings or urge to do something.
抽烟者：哦，“渴望”或“冲动”去做某事。
All right.
好吧。
Interesting.
有趣。
So we've taken a look at these five great words, and I think we should listen to our
所以我们看了这五个好词，我觉得我们应该再听一遍
dialogue again.
我们的对话。
We're going to slow it down just a little bit, and then we'll come back and talk some
我们会稍微放慢速度，然后回来再聊
more.
更多内容。
OK, let's listen.
好的，我们来听吧。
Katerina Ugh, it smells like an ashtray in here.
卡捷琳娜：呃，这里闻起来像烟灰缸。
Smoker Hi honey.
抽烟者：嗨，亲爱的。
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Why do you have that look on your face?
你为什么那副表情？
Katerina What's wrong?
卡捷琳娜：怎么了？
I thought we agreed that you were going to quit smoking.
我以为我们同意你要戒烟了。
Smoker No.
抽烟者：不。
I said I was going to cut down, which is very different.
我说的是我要减少吸烟，这很不一样。
You can't just expect me to go cold turkey overnight.
你不能指望我一下子彻底戒掉。
Katerina Look, there are other ways to quit.
卡捷琳娜：听着，还有其他戒烟的方法。
You can try the nicotine patch or nicotine chewing gum.
你可以试试尼古丁贴片或尼古丁口香糖。
We spend a fortune on cigarettes every month, and now laws are cracking down and not allowing
我们每个月在香烟上花一大笔钱，现在法律也在严厉打击，不允许
smoking in any public place.
在任何公共场所吸烟。
It's not like you can just light up like before.
你不能像以前那样随便点烟了。
Smoker I know, I know.
我知道，我知道。
I really am trying, but I don't have the willpower to just quit.
我真的在努力，但我没有意志力直接戒掉。
I can't fight with the urge to reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee
我无法抵抗早上喝咖啡时伸手拿烟包的冲动，
or after lunch.
或者午饭后。
Please understand.
请理解。
Katerina Fine.
卡捷琳娜，好吧。
I want a divorce.
我要离婚。
And we are back.
我们回来了。
So we have a great part of our show where we like to talk about some phrases that help
我们节目有一个很棒的部分，喜欢讨论一些能帮助你
you attain fluency.
达到流利程度的短语。
That means sounding like a native speaker of English.
这意味着听起来像英语母语者。
And today's phrases are wonderful.
今天的短语非常棒。
Enrique Alright, so let's take a look at them now
恩里克 好的，那我们现在来看看这些短语，
in Fluency Builder.
在流利度构建器里。
Fluency Builder Enrique So on Fluency Builder today, let's take
流利度构建器 恩里克 所以在今天的流利度构建器里，我们来看看
a look at two different phrases.
两个不同的短语。
And let's start with the first one.
我们先从第一个开始。
She mentioned something about going cold turkey overnight.
她提到了“一夜之间彻底戒掉”这个说法。
What is that phrase?
那是什么短语？
Cold turkey?
彻底戒掉？
Katerina Now this is a very strange phrase.
卡捷琳娜 这是一个非常奇怪的短语。
So first of all, why would a turkey be cold?
首先，火鸡怎么会是冷的？
They have lots of feathers.
它们有很多羽毛。
And second of all, what does it have to do with cigarettes?
其次，这和香烟有什么关系？
Enrique Right.
恩里克 对。
So if I say I'm going cold turkey, what is that?
所以如果我说“彻底戒掉”，那是什么意思？
Katerina So just take this as a phrase.
卡捷琳娜 就把它当成一个短语来理解。
Don't think about the actual words because they won't make sense in this context.
别去想字面意思，因为在这个语境下它们说不通。
What we're talking about is quitting smoking entirely.
我们说的是完全戒烟。
You're not going to cut down.
你不是要减少吸烟量。
It means today I'm not going to smoke at all and I'm never going to smoke again.
意思是今天我不抽烟，而且以后再也不抽了。
That means never ever will I smoke another cigarette.
也就是说，我永远不会再抽另一根烟。
So it's cold turkey.
所以就是“彻底戒掉”。
Enrique So if I go cold turkey, it means I stop doing
恩里克 所以如果我说“彻底戒掉”，意思是我立即、
something immediately and suddenly and forever.
突然、永远地停止做某件事。
Katerina Entirely.
卡捷琳娜 完全停止。
Enrique Alright.
恩里克 好的。
Katerina You can use this phrase for different habits, different things that you do like
卡捷琳娜 你可以用这个短语来形容不同的习惯，比如
drinking, for example, or cutting down on sugar.
喝酒，或者减少糖分摄入。
But generally we just say this about cigarettes.
但通常我们只用在香烟上。
Enrique So it's mostly related to smoking.
恩里克 所以它主要和吸烟有关。
Going cold turkey.
彻底戒掉。
Katerina Some people like to smoke less, like one
卡捷琳娜 有些人喜欢少抽点，比如一天一根烟
cigarette a day or one cigarette a week.
或一周一根烟。
But going cold turkey is supposed to be the hardest.
但彻底戒掉被认为是最难的。
Enrique Right.
恩里克 对。
Okay.
好的。
Going cold turkey.
彻底戒掉。
Alright.
好的。
And well, he was explaining the different negative aspects of smoking.
嗯，他解释了吸烟的各种负面影响。
He said, well, you know, they spend a fortune on cigarettes every month.
他说，你知道，他们每个月在香烟上花一大笔钱。
And he said, laws are cracking down.
他还说，法律正在严厉打击。
So if the laws are cracking down, what is he trying to say there?
所以如果法律在严厉打击，他想表达什么？
Katerina Well, this is actually a very interesting
卡捷琳娜 嗯，这其实是一个很有趣的
point because in America right now, it's very hard to smoke in public places.
点，因为现在在美国，在公共场所吸烟非常困难。
So this means that the government is trying to stop people from smoking.
这意味着政府正试图阻止人们吸烟。
So they say, no more smoking in public places, no more smoking in restaurants, no more smoking
所以他们规定，公共场所不准吸烟，餐馆不准吸烟，
in bars.
酒吧也不准吸烟。
And so this means they're cracking down.
所以这就是他们在严厉打击。
They're making it harder to do something.
他们让做某件事变得更难。
Enrique So they are becoming more strict.
恩里克 所以他们变得更严格了。
I think for this phrase, we should listen to a couple of more examples just to make
我觉得对于这个短语，我们应该再听几个例子，
sure we understand it.
确保我们理解它。
Katerina Example one.
卡捷琳娜 例子一。
Enrique The police are cracking down on drunk driving
恩里克 我们城市的警察正在严厉打击
in our city.
酒驾。
Katerina Example two.
卡捷琳娜 例子二。
Enrique Our school has really started to crack down
恩里克 我们学校真的开始严厉打击
on tardiness.
迟到。
Katerina Example three.
卡捷琳娜 例子三。
Enrique The president has passed a law that will
恩里克 总统通过了一项法律，将
crack down possession of illegal substances.
严厉打击持有非法物品。
Enrique Alright, so the government is cracking down.
恩里克 好的，所以政府正在严厉打击。
Laws are cracking down.
法律正在严厉打击。
Katerina Yeah, exactly.
卡捷琳娜 对，没错。
So this is an important one because you read this in the newspapers as well about certain
所以这是一个重要的短语，因为你在报纸上也会读到关于某些
laws and police action.
法律和警察行动的内容。
Enrique Alright, great.
恩里克 好的，很棒。
So I think it's time for us to listen to this dialogue for one last time and then we'll
所以我觉得是时候再听一遍这段对话了，然后我们会
come back and talk a little bit more about this vice.
回来再聊聊这个坏习惯。
Katerina Ah, it smells like an ashtray in here.
卡捷琳娜 啊，这里闻起来像烟灰缸。
Enrique I know, I know.
恩里克 我知道，我知道。
I really am trying but I don't have the willpower to just quit.
我真的在努力，但我没有意志力直接戒掉。
I can't fight with the urge to reach for my pack of smokes in the morning with coffee
我无法抵抗早上喝咖啡时伸手拿烟包的冲动，
or after lunch.
或者午饭后。
Please understand.
请理解。
Katerina Fine, I want a divorce.
卡捷琳娜 好吧，我要离婚。
So do you have a problem with this vice as you call it?
所以，你也有这个你所谓的坏习惯的问题吗？
Are you a smoker?
你抽烟吗？
Enrique I'm really not.
恩里克 我真的不抽。
I'm the type of person that could maybe smoke socially like if we go out to a bar with drinks,
我是那种可能只在社交场合抽烟的人，比如我们去酒吧喝酒的时候，
a social smoker like they call it, right?
就像他们说的社交烟民，对吧？
Katerina Yeah, I'm jealous.
卡捷琳娜 是啊，我嫉妒。
Enrique But not really.
恩里克 但也不是真的。
You're a habitual smoker, right?
你是个习惯性烟民，对吧？
Katerina Right.
卡捷琳娜 对。
Well, I was.
嗯，我以前是。
I'm trying to cut down.
我正在努力减少。
So as a habitual smoker, I often smoked every day.
所以作为一个习惯性烟民，我以前每天都抽烟。
Sometimes I smoked a lot and sometimes I smoked less.
有时抽得多，有时抽得少。
But right now I'm in a period where I'm mostly quit.
但现在我处于一个基本戒掉的阶段。
Enrique Okay, almost.
恩里克 好的，差不多。
Katerina Yeah, well, I haven't smoked in a while.
卡捷琳娜 是啊，嗯，我有一阵子没抽了。
And when I do, it's just one cigarette.
就算抽，也就一根烟。
Enrique Now, it is interesting because like we mentioned,
恩里克 这很有趣，因为就像我们提到的，
laws are cracking down on where you can smoke.
法律正在严厉打击可以吸烟的地方。
But also taxes and cigarettes are becoming much more expensive, right?
而且税收和香烟也变得越来越贵，对吧？
Katerina Absolutely, especially where I'm from in Chicago.
卡捷琳娜 绝对是的，尤其是在我家乡芝加哥。
It's easy to spend maybe 10 US dollars or 12 US dollars on one pack of cigarettes.
一包烟很容易就花掉10美元或12美元。
Enrique On a pack of cigarettes.
恩里克 一包烟。
Imagine that.
想象一下。
So then you have people that can't help smoking one or two packs a day.
所以有些人一天忍不住抽一两包。
So how much is that a month?
那一个月要花多少钱？
It's just an amazing amount of money.
真是一大笔钱。
Katerina Thousands of dollars.
卡捷琳娜 几千美元。
Well, and I have to say, though, a lot of my friends who used to smoke in America have
嗯，但我得说，我在美国很多以前抽烟的朋友
quit.
都戒了。
So this is maybe working.
所以这也许有效。
Enrique The whole thing of making cigarettes more
恩里克 就是让香烟变得更贵
expensive.
这一整套做法。
Katerina Yeah, making them much more expensive.
卡捷琳娜 对，让它们贵得多。
Enrique Now, another interesting thing, and what
恩里克 现在，另一件有趣的事，我最近
I was reading recently, is that you know those warnings that come on cigarette packs that
读到的是，你知道香烟包装上的那些警告，写着
say smoking kales, smoking causes cancer.
“吸烟致癌”。
Actually a study has proven that it's not effective, that people don't mind it or even
实际上，一项研究证明这并不有效，人们不在乎甚至
worry about the cautions on the cigarette packages.
不担心香烟包装上的警告。
Katerina Well, as a smoker, I could say that, yeah,
卡捷琳娜 嗯，作为一个烟民，我可以说，是啊，
you generally, if you're going to smoke a cigarette, don't look at the label that much.
你通常，如果你要抽烟，不会太看那个标签。
You just, you know, you throw it in your bag and you forget about it.
你只是，你知道，把它扔进包里就忘了。
Enrique But it's actually gotten to the point where
恩里克 但实际上已经到了人们
people choose the cigarette pack based on the picture.
根据图片来选择香烟包装的地步。
So it's like, oh yeah, give me the one with the black lungs or give me that one.
所以就像，“哦，给我那个有黑肺的，或者给我那个。”
Katerina Oh, God.
卡捷琳娜 哦，天哪。
Enrique Yeah, it's interesting.
恩里克 是啊，这很有趣。
So it's not really working.
所以它其实没什么用。
I guess we're going to have to find other ways to make people more conscious about this
我想我们得找其他方法让人们更意识到这个
vice.
坏习惯。
Katerina We should.
卡捷琳娜 我们应该。
Enrique But come to our website at EnglishPod.com.
恩里克 但请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Tell us what you think about this vice, smoking.
告诉我们你对这个坏习惯——吸烟的看法。
Is it good?
它好吗？
Is it bad?
它坏吗？
Are you a habitual smoker or just a social smoker?
你是习惯性烟民还是只是社交烟民？
Katerina Yeah, we also have lots of great stuff, tools
卡捷琳娜 是啊，我们网站上还有很多很棒的东西、工具
for you on our website and expansion sentences and all that stuff that helps you continue
供你使用，还有扩展句子等等，能帮助你在
your studies outside of, well, the car or your house.
车里或家里之外继续学习。
So check it out.
所以去看看吧。
Let us know what you think.
告诉我们你的想法。
And until next time.
下次再见。
Enrique All right, we'll see you there.
恩里克 好的，我们那里见。
Bye.
拜拜。
Katerina Bye.
卡捷琳娜 拜拜。